Rafia Khandaker

New York, NY | (516) 491-4984 | RafiaKhandaker@gmail.com LinkedIn | Github | Blog

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Full Stack Developer with a passion for continued learning, experienced in JavaScript, React, Ruby on Rails, and SQL. A background in Social Media marketing, I realized my joy for creating content that resonates with people. Through programming, I find satisfaction in how many creative ways there are to solve a problem. I bring strong skills in project management, a fine eye to detail, and a strong desire to drive a vision to fruition in an aesthetic manner.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Full-Stack: Javascript, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, SQL, React, Active Record, PostgreSQL, SQLite, RESTful APIs

Design: Canva, Illustrator, Lightroom, Photoshop, HTML/CSS, Figma

Social Media: Khoros, Digimind, Google Analytics, Facebook Analytics, Pinterest Analytics

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Concert Buddy - Github

View concerts from your favorite artists, add yourself to a list of attendees, and meet fellow concertgoers in New York City.

- Implemented authentication and password protection in Rails for users to sign-up or login using tokens.
- Designed a React frontend and cohesive styling elements through Figma.
- Built out a full CRUD functionality for users to personalize their accounts.

FiDi Dinina Guide - Github

Single-page application with searchable listings of restaurants, cafes, and bars in the Financial District, Manhattan.

- Constructed client-side routes with React Router and RESTful routing conventions.
- Features search function to filter by type of establishment, street address, or name.
- Developed an API of location listings in a SQLite database with the ability to persist data for new listings.

Poemland - Github

Writing-prompt application that provides users daily randomized lyrics off of which to base a poem.

- Utilized a Ruby Sinatra API backend using Active Record to access database information.
- Generated a React frontend with ability for users to create an account that saves their daily poems.
- Incorporated forms to create and edit poems that persist to the backend.

EXPERIENCE

Publishers Clearing House Jericho, NY

Social Media Coordinator

06/2016 - 07/2022 09/2018 - 07/2022

- Revamped and modernized brand styling through eye-catching visuals and engaging copy to millions of followers across Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, YouTube and Pinterest.
- Increased Instagram impressions and engagement over 100%, video views over 50%, and followers over 20% year-over-year.
- Advised a customer service team with other team leads ahead of new promotions and addressed user concerns.
- Led creative initiatives for e-commerce promotions and A/B testing in social media and acquisitions campaigns.

Project Management Intern

06/2016 - 08/2018

- Supported the Project Manager on the Interactive Development team, by assisting with mobile application launches, site updates, email campaigns, video shoots, event promotions, and social media initiatives.
- Launched and tracked 40-70 projects weekly, managing resources across a team of 25-30 creatives and coordinating project tasks and deadlines.
- Onboarded users to workflow management platforms and resolved technical issues.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School New York, NY

08/2022 - 11/2022

Full Stack Development: Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Stony Brook University Stony Brook, NY

Graduated 05/2018